3287 South Drive Caledonia, NY 14423 March 27, 2013

Dan Greer Area Director in the Center for Residence Life Rochester Institute of Technology 1 Lomb Memorial Drive Rochester, NY 14623

Dear Mr. Greer,

Enclosed please find my application and resume for a Graduate Assistantship at Rochester Institute of Technology. In May I will graduate from Nazareth College of Rochester with my B.A. in Sociology. In September I will embark on my journey to achieve my M.S. in Higher Education Student Affairs Administration from Nazareth College. I am impressed by the rich variety of academic, elective, and extra-curricular activities that RIT offers to its diverse student population. I also highly value the Division of Student Affairs' vision to develop the nation's most engaged campus community.

Presently, I act as a Student Aide in the Department of Residential Life at Nazareth College. Here, I collaborate with the Director, Assistant Director, and Area Directors of Residential Life to improve students' overall campus life experiences. Specifically, I support the Residential Life team in testing an on-line housing selection system. The Residential Life team uses these assessment results to make necessary adjustments to the system before campus-wide use. In addition, I have also collaborated with Nazareth's Student Development staff to create an engaging and informative presentation for transfer students.

I have worked as a Student Aide in the Education Department at Monroe Community College as well. In this position, I worked with the secretary to successfully and efficiently manage student accounts and profiles. Furthermore, I assisted the Chair of the Education Department during large advisement sessions. During these advisement sessions I supported students in selecting appropriate courses needed to fulfill their specific degree requirements.

Additionally, for the last four years I have worked with youth, ages 5-17, in a local summer recreation program. As a supervisor of the program, I have gained essential group management and organizational techniques, as well as developed positive relationships with the youth.

I would truly appreciate an opportunity to interview with you, and can be reached at (585) 730-3507. Thank you for your consideration.

Sincerely,

3287 South Drive • Caledonia, NY 14423 • Cell Phone (585) 730-3507 • Permanent (585) 538-4729 • mcornwe5@mail.naz.edu

EDUCATION Nazareth College of Rochester

B.A. Sociology

Anticipated May 2013 GPA: 3.98 M.S. Higher Education Student Affairs

Beginning Fall 2013

Dean's List, three semesters

The Honor Society of Phi Kappa Phi

Pi Gamma Mu International Honor Society in Social Sciences

HIGHER EDUCATION EXPERIENCE Nazareth College Residential Life Office, Rochester, NY (January 2013-Present)

Student Aide- Assist staff in completing various preparatory tasks for student events, activities, college conferences, and orientations. These tasks include, booking space and catering for conferences/student events, collaborating with peers and staff to determine content for orientations, while also providing assistance in preparing the MyHousing @ Naz computer system for the Fall 2013 housing selection process.

Monroe Community College Completed 75 Total Credits

Dean's List, two semesters

(9/08-12/10)

A.A. Liberal Arts Childhood Education

Monroe Community College Education Office, Rochester, NY (Spring 2010-Fall 2010) Student Aide – Helped manage student profiles and accounts. Assisted education office staff during two large advisement sessions. Completed various administrative tasks including, designing bulletin boards, creating brochures, and completing excel spreadsheets.

Tutor – Provided one-on-one support for students of all majors, assisting with writing skills and study strategies as well as acting as a source of motivation and encouragement.

JOB EXPERIENCE

Best Buy Sales Support, Victor, NY (October 2012-January 2013) Supported the sales team in multiple aspects including and not limited to stocking, receiving shipments, picking online orders, and managing warehouse functions.

Caledonia Summer Recreation, Caledonia, NY (Summers 2009-2012) *Supervisor* – Supervise students between the ages of 5-17 in a 7-week program designed to engage youth in activities such as playing games/sports and creating crafts. Design and participate in activities, as well as planning and chaperoning field trips. Communicate regularly with parents regarding questions and concerns. Manage any student behavior issues.

EDUCATION FIELD WORK

T.J. Connor Elementary School, Scottsville, NY (Summer 2012) French Road Elementary School, Pittsford, NY (Spring 2012) Nathaniel Hawthorne School #25, Rochester, NY (Fall 2011) St. Pius X School, Chili, NY (Spring 2010)

Took part in managing the classroom, designing engaging lessons, and interacting with students from a variety of backgrounds. Collaborated with various professionals within a school setting.

COLLEGE ACTIVITIES

Homework Help Program, Nazareth College of Rochester (Spring 2011)

Tutor – Worked with high school students from Rochester City School District, providing support and assistance with completing homework assignments and preparing for tests.

COMMUNITY SERVICE

Volunteer Coach, Caledonia, NY, (12/07-4/08)

Helped coach young kids, ages 6-12 years old, who took part in Biddy Basketball and Little League Baseball. Managed practices and designed related sports activities.

COMPUTER

PC and Macintosh

SKILLS Proficient in Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Internet, E-mail